Lingess Rajoo

Software Engineer

Lingessrajoo@gmail.com • +1 (765) 409 4856 San Francisco, CA 94115 linkedin.com/in/lingess-rajoo github.com/Lrajoo

Analytical professional with hands-on experience in contributing to the product development lifecycle on both frontend and backend by building reusable React components and RESTful APIs using agile principles. Effective communicator with excellent relationship building skills; possesses a flexible attitude with strong problem solving and organizational building abilities.

Technical Proficiencies

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C, C++, PHP, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Angular, Node.js, Django
Testing Frameworks: Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Selenium

Software Tools: Git, MobX, Redux, Figma, Ant Design, Jenkins, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Single-Spa

Certifications: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Career Experience

Steerwise Inc, San Francisco CA

Software Developer

June 2020 - Present

- Participated in architecting the current application into React micro frontends using an MVVM pattern.
- Implemented Test-Driven Development using Mocha, Chai, and Enzyme to ensure code is written the right way.
- Refactored existing monolithic application into multiple SPA micro frontends to provide a seamless transition.
- Rendered technical support to the existing Angular application by executing new features and bug fixes.

Flockjay Inc, San Francisco CA

Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - May 2020

- Designed and updated frontend code of social media platform with more than 100 reusable React components.
- Implemented RESTful API endpoints in Node.js to drive and engage user experience on the frontend.
- Raised completion rates by 20% through restructuring and revitalizing the program's application user interface.
- Reduced production deployments by utilizing a service where website links are dynamically polled from Airtable.

Earlybird Alert System (EPICS – Purdue University), West Lafayette IN Software Lead

June 2018 - Dec 2018

- Built the interface by utilizing Bootstrap to enhance how caseworkers manage at-risk clients.
- Created the backend by using PHP to improve the text and email notifications response time by 50%.
- Introduced documentation on the existing product and features to ensure new members meet requirements.
- Mentored incoming members and equipping them with skills and tools to contribute to the codebase.

Projects

Spiria (Senior Design – Purdue University)

- Produced a test sequence to preliminarily predict Parkinson's disease using the spiral test under 5 minutes.
- Deployed the backend using a Diango framework to calculate the test results by comparing them to a dataset.
- User data collected on the Raspberry Pi communicates with the backend to store spiral test data in the database.

Education

Purdue University, West Lafayette IN Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Innovation May 2019